Kimberly Reddick



kim.reddick@icloud.com



linkedin.com/in/kimreddick



405-221-0145



http://github.com/flirtara

Summary

I have 20+ years of progressive experience providing support and leadership while managing the inter-relationship between various departments within highly complex organizational structures. I have a superior record of optimizing large-scale, mission-critical projects on time while exceeding quality assurance expectations. I am experienced in the strategic detail planning, execution, and leadership of enterprise-wide technology initiatives, which support business goals, deliver continuous improvement, and boost productivity.

Experience



IBM Security Access Manager / Cloud Identity Operations | IBM

Aug 2014 - Present (7 years 5 months +)

Lighthouse was acquired by IBM and rebranded to Cloud Identity Services. I was charged with developing and delivering custom Identity and Access Management solutions hosted in the Cloud. I also installed and configured multi-tenant WebSEAL instances, junctions, pop, ACLs, and authorization rules.

- Migrated customer LDAP data between different environments and utilize TFIM Federations to troubleshoot and debug SPNEGO WebSEAL configuration.
- ► Leveraged personal wiki to house training documentation focused on new employees.
- ▶ Played a key role in helping new employees transition into our organization smoother, by providing documentation, training, and mentoring.
- Directed project to migrate large customers from old environments to new environments, which included moving ISAM, ISIM, custom application components, scripts, and database content.
- ► Created and maintained custom template scripts to generate all the pdadmin scripts needed to build the ISAM WebSEAL junctions, pops, ACLs, and any policies for the dedicated customer environment.
- ► Engineered scripts to automate the daily export and archive all ISAM WebSEAL junction configuration for each WebSEAL instance, which included all junctions and policies to HTML format on a website for team retrieval.



Tivoli Security Services Engineer | Lighthouse Computer Services

Lighthouse Computer Services, A Converge Company

Mar 2014 - Aug 2014 (6 months)

I functioned as the Security Access Manager (ISAM), IBM Security Identity Manager (ISIM), Tivoli Federated Identity Management (TFIM), and any custom components into the company's environment. I played a critical role on the team by transitioning customers from the Identity Management Solution

into the company's custom cloud identity architecture. This initiative involved partnering with the customer to migrate IBM.

- Assisted ISAM and ISIM Environment install and configuration, which included performance tuning and provisioning policy modifications to work within the company's infrastructure.
- ► Introduced to Tivoli Directory Integrator (TDI) assembly line development and assisted in migrating customer assembly lines into the company's environment.
- ► Charged with configuring, testing, and updating CA Workload Automation ESP scripts to allow the customer to trigger TDI assembly lines.
- ► Successfully documented and assisted other users on setting up Eclipse Based Environment to build an External Authentication Interface (EAI). Used Gradle, Jetty, and SVN client.



Systems Management Specialist | CDI Talent & Technology Solutions

CDI Talent & Technology Solutions

Feb 2012 - Feb 2014 (2 years 1 month)

In this role, I provided support for IBM Identity Management (ITIM) Environment for SO Delivery, Security, and Risk Management while serving as a member of the Boarding Team. I functioned as the ITIM administrator while supporting the boarding team to board AIX, Linux, and zLinux servers into the ITIM application. This initiative enabled the management of user and group accounts.

- Executed security scans and collaborated with System Administrators to mitigate issues and ensure servers complied with ITIM standards for boarding.
- ► Supported the GSA project, which included scripting to automation to facilitate tracking and processing of data.
- ▶ Provided scripting support when required to implement new features into the boarding process.
- Trained co-workers on new processes and provided training to enhance their Unix skills.
- Completed documentation support to review, update, and provide suggestions to maintain concise, current documented procedures.



Solaris System Administrator | Computer System Designers, LLC. (CSD)

Computer System Designers, LLC. (CSD)

Oct 2011 - Feb 2012 (5 months)

As a Solaris System Administrator, I provided support for DISA Solaris System Branch while utilizing (Solaris, BMC BladeLogic, Remedy Ticket Management System, Scripting). Additionally, I performed security scans and mitigated issues to ensure servers complied with DISA Security standards.

- ◆ Aided with quarterly live upgrades of Solaris Cluster Patches.
- ► Supported TIER III application organizations, including troubleshooting, configuration changes, server reboots, and data gathering.

 Mentored new employees and utilized BMC BladeLogic to automate information gathering and auditing. Performed various scripts across multiples servers.

Solaris Systems Administrator | SAIC

SAIC

Feb 2011 - Oct 2011 (9 months)

In this role, I provided support for DISA Solaris System Branch utilizing (Solaris, BMC BladeLogic, Remedy Ticket Management System, Scripting). Additionally, I performed security scans and fixed issues to ensure servers complied with DISA Security standards.

- Utilized BMC BladeLogic to automate information gathering while auditing and performing certain scripts across multiples servers.
- ◆ Assisted with quarterly Live Upgrades of Solaris Cluster Patches.
- Supported TIER III Application Organizations including troubleshooting, configuration changes, server reboots, and data gathering.
- Popened and tracked tickets internally and with vendors to ensure problem resolution.

Software Engineer | VSN Inc.

VSN Inc

Sep 2005 - Feb 2011 (5 years 6 months)

As a Software Engineer, I delivered world-class support for Web Portal Infrastructure while focusing on Security that utilized IBM Products (IBM/Tivoli Identity Manager, Tivoli Access Manager, Tivoli Directory Server, WAS ND). I successfully installed, configured, tested, and maintained IBM Tivoli Identity Manager, adapters, life cycles, and workflows.

- ► Successfully configured and maintained provisioning / de-provisioning services and policies for multiple oid sync targets.
- Managed and resolved user registration, password reset, and authentication issues, including CAC authentication.
- ▶ Provided Tivoli Access Manager for eBusiness support for application deployment support, including creating and configuring users, groups, ACLs, junctions, JMT entries, and certificates.
- ► IBM Directory Server and Integrator support including data imports, exports, and consistency for application troubleshooting

Education



Oklahoma State

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, COMPUTER SCIENCE 1994 - 1996



University of Oklahoma

Licenses & Certifications

XML Essential Training - Lynda.com

Virtualization Essential Training - Lynda.com
B60F8E

- The Ultimate Guide to Game Development with Unity 2019 Udemy UC-PB14X7OR
- **Beginning VS Code** Udemy UC-8Z7JYLBY
- The Ultimate Guide to 2D Mobile Game Development with Unity Udemy UC-0FJHYA39
- Inkscape Game Design: Inkscape 2D Game Design, Inkscape Tips Udemy UC-SQIERIPX
- Unity C# Survival Guide Udemy
 UC-R25505EY
- **Learn How To Code Games In Roblox Studio** Udemy UC-66c57894-3720-4434-a999-081d63545164
- Roblox Advanced Coding Course Udemy UC-bd61fa6f-39a8-4cf5-b482-5258a02c8912

UC-f0073f27-6490-443f-b8e4-d7779857553e

- Roblox Programming and Game Creation Udemy UC-7bfdaeca-74df-4908-9987-bd40e9be73fc.pdf
- CrazyTalk 8.1 3D Avatar Talking Head/Lip Sync Video Creation Udemy
- Quick Introduction to Postman Beginners Udemy UC-f77e44cd-3797-41fe-b92a-dd88d655bb3b
- Microservices Architecture The Complete Guide Udemy

Blockchain and Bitcoin Fundamentals - Udemy

UC-400aa7e3-5c2c-435d-8472-d5492e342a6e

Bitcoin Advanced Level: Transactions - Udemy

UC-80003b98-178b-4caf-9065-f535d403f541

Software Architecture: REST API Design = The Complete Guide - Udemy

UC-80abfa08-b5cb-44af-8907-79c7579f95d3

Blockchain Advanced Level: Uses Beyond Bitcoin - Udemy

UC-eee989bf-6f15-4531-88ec-77227d86cf37

Git & Github Master Course (2021) - Udemy

UC-e2342bba-2137-45e8-864f-e18fdc7b5f2b

Automated Software Testing with Python - Udemy

UC-2f6d8aeb-cae0-4ce3-b12e-d575e6eec04a

Ansible for the Absolute Beginner - Hands-On - DevOps - Udemy

UC-42c704d5-a55d-425b-8a1f-5693f9e2040e

Docker - SWARM - Hands-on-DevOps - Udemy

UC-83f7cfb3-4049-42b7-940f-583720d578ac

Introduction to Containers, Kubernetes, and OpenShift V2 - Cognitive Class

3c32b8284fbb432a80ed3b857f956cd6

Getting started with Microservices with Istio and IBM Cloud Kubernetes Service

- Cognitive Class

208e9669b6da4b78bf7ecb08184b29b6

Getting started with Microservices with Istio and IBM Cloud Kubernetes Service

- IBM

Build a Backend REST API with Python & Django - Advanced - Udemy

UC-4221a016-6cd9-46e8-ab7e-f033465a83d4

Skills

IBM Security Identity Manager • IBM Tivoli Directory Integrator • Unix Systems Administration • Technical Documentation • System Administration • Python (Programming Language) • C# • Git • Shell Scripting • Travis CI